

Visual finesse and better experiences drive my work wagon. The challenge to play in the hybrid space, an infusion of design and technology is exciting and fulfilling. My specialities include Human Computer Interaction, Design Research, Data Visualisation, User Experience Design, and Story-boarding.

Experience

Microsoft, India Development Center
User Experience Design Intern, Jul 2017-Dec 2017

Freelance

Digital illustrations for educational game **Monster Math**. Branding for publishing startup **Flying Penguin**. Wall graffiti for cakeshop **E=MC2**.

Deloitte-USI, Bangalore, India Business Analyst - Cyber Security, Jul 2014-Jul 2015

General Electric, Bangalore, India Software Developer Intern, Jan 2014-Jun 2014

IBM, Bangalore, India Software Developer Intern, Jul 2013-Aug 2013

College Editorial Board MIT, Manipal, India Creative Head of council of 40 students, 2013-2014

Education

Hochschule für Technik und Wirtschaft, Berlin, Germany (Exchange Student) Communication Design, Sep 2016-Feb 2017

National Institute of Design, Bangalore, India M.Des in Information Design, 2015-2017

Manipal Institute of Technology, MAHE, Manipal, India B.Tech in Computer Science, 2010-2014 | 8.6 CGPA

St. Michael's High School, Patna, India CBSE, 1998-2010 | XIIth 92%, Xth 95%

Achievements

UXIndia 2017 - Student Gold Award
Interact 2017 - Paper Presentation & Publication
Adobe Design Achievement Awards 2017 - Semifinalist
Information is Beautiful Awards 2017 - Longlist
IndiaHCI 2016 - Paper Presentation & Publication
D'Vibes Deloitte Annual Fest 2015 - Best Logo
Microsoft Windows App Hackathon, Manipal, 2013 - Second Prize
Revels - Manipal Cultural Fest 2010-14 - Awards in Fine Arts & Cartooning
Techniche, IIT-G 2010 - School Student Shortlist
Best Michaelite, 2010 - Consistent performance for 12 years at school

Good At

Adobe Photoshop
Adobe Illustrator
Adobe XD
Sketch
Principle
Flinto
HTML/CSS
Javascript
Prototyping
Story-Boarding

Interests

User Experience
User Interface
Design Research
Information Architecture
Data Visualisation
Graphic Design

Summing it Up!



E: myspace.atul@gmail.com

W: www.atulkr.com linkedin.com/in/atul-kr be.net/_atul_kumar twitter.com/_atul_kumar instagram.com/_atul_kumar